Guide to the Ford Madox Ford collection, [ca. 1850]-1973
Ford, Ford Madox collection,
- Series III. Incoming correspondence and manuscripts by others
  - N-O
    - Noot, Edmee van der AL[postcard]S to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, Sept.12, 1906; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 36)
      Hammersmith; Dear Mistress Hueffer/ Thank you very much for your letter which I only got yesterday. [Lamb collection]
    - Noot, Edmee van der AL[postcard]S to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, Sept.17, 1906; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 37)
      London; Dear Mistree Hueffer/ Thank you very much for your interesting letter. [Lamb collection]
    - Noot, Edmee van der AL[postcard]S to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, Sept.27, 1906; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 38)
      Hammersmith; Dear Mistress Hueffer/ We arrived here. The children all right, yesterday at 4 o'clock [Lamb collection]
    - Noot, Edmee van der AL[postcard]S to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, Oct.18, 1910; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 39)
      Belgium; My dear Elsie/ Thank you for your card which I got this morning. In a few minutes [Lamb collection]
    - Noot, Edmee van der ALS to Katherine Hueffer Lamb, Apr.26, 1964; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 40)
      Bruxelles; My dearest little B.A.B.S./ Knowing that you had many visits on your agenda before being settled again [Lamb collection]
    - ?, Norman ALS to Violet Hunt, Jan.4, 1857; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 41)
      London; Cuckoo sweetheart! Isn't it odd? Thanks ever to much for thinking of writing [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Norris, James ALS to Alfred William Hunt, Jun.4, 1857; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 42)
      Corpus Christie College; Dear Hunt/ I send you herewith a copy of the new Statutes. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - The North Eastern Railway ALS to Margaret Raine Hunt, Jun.3, 1903; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 43)
      York; Madam/ I have your letter of the 23rd ult. enclosing two Dividend Warrants re New Stock 1901 [Violet Hunt papers]
    - O'Connel, Janice TL[telegram] to Irene Cockrane, Mar.8, 1951; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 2 envelopes (Box 87, Folder 44)
      New York; Interested Televisiion rights Hunts Corsican Sisters [Original and correction + 2 envelopes]
    - Odom, W. TL[copy] to Miss Higgins, Aug.26, 1930; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 45)
      [n.p.] Dear Miss Higgins, I am interested to hear that a Life is being written of your Great-Aunt, [1 leaf is notes about E. E. Siddal] [Viiolet Hunt papers]
    - O'Leery, Con, May 2, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 46)
      London; Dear Mrs. Hueffer, I am extremely sorry that I must diappoint myself for Tuesday. [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Olivet College, Trustees of DS Honorary D. Letters ... Ford Madox Ford, June, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 47)
      Olivet; [Diploma for Doctor of Letters in padded Ollivet College folder; signed by Joseph Brewer, President]
    - Olivet College TLS to Janice Biala, Jan.6, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 48)
      Olivet; Dearest Janice: I have been much longer getting back to Olivet than I expected [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Janice Biala, Feb.7, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 49)
      Olivet; Dearest Janice: I cannot tell you how pleased I was to get your letter of Jan. 30th. [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Jan.20, 1938; 3 leaves (Box 87, Folder 50)
      Olivet; Dear Mr. Ford: It's shocking of me not to have written you long before now. [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Oct.25, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 51)
      Olivet; Dear Ford: That was a handsome piece in the PW and is going to be, I know, very helpful [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Nov.1, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 52)
      Olivet; Dear Ford: I have been long answering your letter of October 24, partly because I have been away, [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Nov.4, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 53)
      Olivet; Dear Ford: I am embarrassed to think that I have not long since sent Janice the rest of what I owe her [Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Feb.24, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 54)
      Olivet; Dear Ford: I cannot tell you how nice it is to have a letter from you and to know that you are coming along [Signed Joseph Brewer
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Mar.9, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 55)
      Olivet; Dear Ford: I cannot tell you how delighted I was to have your good letter and how excited we all are [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College, Mar.17, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 56)
      Olivet; My dear Ford: I am delighted that the dates suit you all right and I am tremendously pleased [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Mar.21, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 57)
      Olivet; Dear Ford: The English-Speaking Union in Detroit would very much like to have you come and talk [Signed Joseph Brewer] [Verso contains Ford's draft response]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Mar.31, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 58)
      Olivet; My dear Ford: Thanks for you very nice letter of the 24th. I think I understand a little more [Signed Joseph Brewer]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford & Janice Biala, [1938?]; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 59)
      Olivet; Dear Ford and Janice: That telegram I sent you in Paoili came from Sewickley, Pa [Signed Robert G. Ramsay]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Nov.15, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 60)
      Olivet; My dear Ford: I am returning the Baltsell communication concerning Bill Dole's application [Signed Robert G. Ramsay]
    - Olivet College TLS to Ford, Mar.13, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 61)
      Olive; My dear Ford: We are excited about the news of your proposed visit. While I am sorry it will [Signed Robert G. Ramsay]
    - Olson, Charles John ALS to Ford, May 26, [1939?]; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 61.5)
      Gloucester; My dear Ford- I wanted to send you this goodbye. I felt a loss when I heard from Dahlberg
    - Omond, T. S. ALS to Ford, Apr.26, 1904; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 62)
      Tunbridge Wells; My dear Sir, What a delightful letter you have sent me! [Lamb collection]
    - Omond, T.S. ALS to Ford, Jun.17, 1904; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 63)
      Dear Mr. Hueffer/ "A man convinced against his will is of the same opinion still," so I won't contest yours [Lamb collection]
    - Omond, T. S. ALS to Ford, Aug.9, 1904; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 64)
      Bridge N.B.; Dear Mr. Hueffer/ Your letter finding me on holiday, has staid too long unanswered [Lamb collection]
    - Omond, T. S. ALS to Ford, Sept.16, 1904; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 65)
      Edinburgh; Dear Mr. Hueffer/ I am sorry to hear of your break down, [Lamb collection]
    - Opinion TLS to Ford, Feb.27, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 66)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: A friend of mine, Mr. Edward Robbin, who has just returned from Paris [Signed James Waterman Wise] [Draft of Ford letter to Status Office, Whitehall on verso. Difficult to read full text.]
    - Orage, Alfred Richard ALS to Ford, Aug.8, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 67)
      London; My dear F.M.F. Our friend E.P. tells me you are willing to join our little conspiracy
    - Orage, Alfred Richard ALS to Ford, Aug.18, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 68)
      London; My dear F.M.F. It hasn't been so formal as that. All I've done is to publish several articles
    - Orchardson, Sir William Quiller ALS to Alfred William Hunt, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 69)
      London; My dear Hunt/ I am very sorry about the result of the elections last night. Though you were very near [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Orr, A. TL[copy] to Violet Hunt, Jul.25, [?]; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 70)
      Isle of Man; Dear Violet, I daresay Mr. Crawfurd only meant to assert as much as was true, [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Owen, Philip Cunliffe ALS to Francis Hueffer, Jan.20, 1870; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 87, Folder 71)
      London; Dear Sir, I have been absent for a few days and otherwise much engaged
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ruth Aley, Jul.17, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 72)
      New York; Dear Mrs. Aley: I am enclosing herewith contracts in duplicate for Mr. Ford's COLLECTED POEMS [Signed Clulow, H. V.
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Janice Biala, Mar.19, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 73)
      Wooster; Dear Mrs. Ford: Thank you for yours of March 5. I am leaving tonight for California, to be gone two weeks [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Janice Biala, Mar.20, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 74)
      New York; The Oxford University Press acknowledges the safe receipt of illustrations [Unsigned]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Janice Biala, Jun.9, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 75)
      New York; Dear Mrs. Ford: I shall change my plan about holding your drawings here and in the the light of your [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Janice Biala, Aug.25, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 76)
      New York; Dear Mrs. Ford: I have today written a letter to Mr. Ford which I hope may serve as a reply [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Janice Biala, Feb.8, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 77)
      New York; Dear Mrs. Ford: Your letter of February the seventh has been handed to me. I will see that [Signed Paul Willert]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, May 30, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 78)
      Wooster; My dear Mr. Ford: Your letter of 26 May has been forwarded to me here. We shall be pleased [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Jun.25, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 79)
      Wooster; Dear Mr. Ford: Thank you very much for your letter of June 18. I have forwardeed to Mr. Clulow [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Aug.21, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 80)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: Mrs. Aley has written me that she has now received your contracts but that several [Signed Margaret Nicholson]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Oct.3, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 81)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: Your letter of September 23 has come to me as Dr. Lowry is not in the office. [Signed Margaret Nicholson]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Oct.18, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 82)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I hope you will believe that a hard working editor ambitious for his list [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Jan.17, 1936; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 83)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I took flight from New York on Jan. 3d and have had an opportunity to find out [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Feb.13, 1936; 2 leaves (Box 87, Folder 84)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: My visit in London was very brief. Upon my return here, I find your contracts [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Mar.30, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 85)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: I am taking the liberty of answering your letter of March 18 as Dr. Lowry is not [Signed Margaret Nicholson]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Apr.1, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 86)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: This is to assure you that your manuscript has now reached us safely. [Signed Margaret Nicholson]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Apr.8, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 87)
      New York; Dear Sir: Under separate cover, we are sending you a parcel containing two sets of proof [Signed John Barbour]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Jun.5, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 88)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: I have been very busy going over the proofs of your poems and editing the manuscript [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Jun.24, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 89)
      New York; Dear Sir: We are sending you under separate cover, the proofs of your book and we trust that they [SignedJohn Barbour]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Jun.24, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 90)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: Both your and Mrs. Ford's letter of June 13 have reached us. We note your refusal [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TL[telegram]S to Ford, Jul.17, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 91)
      London; Dear Sir: In reply to your letter of the 14th, we have no correspondence here and you are [Signed GFJ Cumberlege]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Jul.30, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 92)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: In accordance with our recent advices from London, I am authorized to print a maximum [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Aug.25, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 93)
      New York; Dear Sir: Upon my return to our office this morning after a brief holiday I found your letter of August 12 [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Sept.2, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 94)
      London; Dear Sir: Mr. Lowry of our New York office has sent me copies of your letter to him [Signed G.F.J. Cumberlege]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Sept.11, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 95)
      London; Dear Sir: I am very glad to get your letter of the 10th and I cabled New York [Signed G. F. J. Cumberlege]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Sept.23, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 96)
      London; Dear Mr. Ford: Your letter was handed me by my secretary ten minutes before my train to Southampton [SignedG. F. J. Cumberlege]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Sept.24, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 97)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: This is to let you know that we have received from you today the proofs [Signed Margaret Nicholson]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Oct.6, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 98)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I must start with an apology for my hurried letter of September the twenty-third [Signed G. F. J. Cumberlege]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Oct.21, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 99)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: I have been following the correspondence between Mr. Cumberlege andyou and am glad [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Nov.24, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 100)
      New York; My dear Mr. Ford: I am enclosing your copyright certificate and our statement for the expense [Signed Howard F. Lowry]
    - Oxford University Press TLS to Ford, Mar.3, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 87, Folder 101)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford: We are considering selling off the remainders of COLLECTED POEMS [Signed J. B. Orrick]
  - P-R
    - P AL[fragment]S to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 1)
      [n.p.] ... Little (sketches) or plans & getting rooms built -- all from a sick bed -- designing cottages etc. [Lamb collection]
    - P TLS to Elsie Martindale Hueffer, [1948?]; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 2)
      [n.p.] My Dear Elsie, I was interested in what you said about Goldring. I think some men get irritable [Lamb collection]
    - Paget, Violet, "Vernon Lee" ALS to Ford, Oct.17, 1908; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 3)
      Florence; Dear Mr. Hueffer, My return to [Wa--] having been a little delayed I sent for the copy of the [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Paget, Violet, "Vernon Lee" ALS to Ford, Nov.2, 1908; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 4)
      Florence; Dear Mr. Hueffer, I hope you like the "Virgin of the 7 Daggers?" My sister in law wishes [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Paget, Violet, "Vernon Lee" ALS to Ford, Nov.12, 1908; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 5)
      Florence; Dear Mr. Hueffer, My sister in law, widow of the late Eurgene Lee-Hamilton, [?] me to forward you the accompany [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Palgrave, Sir Reginald Francis Douce ALS to Alfred William Hunt, Dec.11, 1885; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 88, Folder 6)
      London; My dear Mr. Hunt- I've been out of town, or I'd sooner have answered your note, as you may be sure, [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Pankhurst, Dame Christabel TLS to Ford, Jun.4, 1910; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 7)
      London; Dear Mr.Hueffer, Your invitation to speak gives me great pleasure, and I wish that I could accept it, [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Parker, Dorothy Rothschild to Ford, Nov.2, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 8)
      New York; Dear Mr. & Mrs. Ford: Two distinguished Americans are returning from Spain today
    - Paterson, Isabel TLS to Ford, [1931+?]; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 9)
      [n.p.] My dear Ford, Probably you wouldn't have seen my review of "Return to Yesterday" when the book came out
    - Patmore, Brigit Ethel Elizabeth Morrison-Scott TL[copy] to Violet Hunt, Dec.30, 1914; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 10)
      London; My dear Violet, Thank you many times for the Christmas remembrance, I have been wondering
    - Paul, Maurice Den ALS toViolet Hunt, Sept.20, 1908; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 11)
      Parkstone, Dorset; Miss Hunt in [?] with M. Eden Paul, M.D. Mrs. Hunt's maintenance {Bill for Margaret Raine Hunt while at Moorcroft] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Peacock, Anne ALS to Silvia Hunt Fogg Elliot, May 23, [n.y.]; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 12)
      [n.p.] My dear Silvia/ Your flowers came yesterday and after arranging and admiring them I intended to send a card [Also included on same leaf is Margaret Raine Hunt's AL[fragment] to Silvia] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Peacock, George Miscellaneous envelopes & letters to Peacock, 1824-1858; 2 leaves + 14 envelopes (Box 88, Folder 13)
      [Miscellaneous envelopes and letters all address to George Peacock (Professor, Dean, Reverend)] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Peacock, Hannah AM Diary for 1825, 1825; 33 leaves (Box 88, Folder 14)
      [n.p.] [Small booklet with notations of daily events] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Peacock, Hannah AM Two Poems, [1825?]; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 15)
      [n.p.] ["But now at thirty years my hair is grey" and "No man no more. Oh! never more on me"; found in 1825 diary] [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Peacock, Hannah ALS to Violet Hunt, Apr.30, 1867; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 16)
      [Durham] My dear little Violet/ It is so long since I had a talk with you, I must write you a short letter [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Pearn, Pollinger & Higham, Ltd. TLS to Stella Bowen, 1940-1948; 42 leaves +14 leaves (Box 88, Folder 16.5)
      London; [42 letters from February 1, 1940 to December 9, 1948 with contracts for Ford and some royalty statements] [Julian Loewe papers]
    - Pearn, Pollinger & Higham, Ltd. TLS to Esther Julia Madox Loewe, Nov.3, 1947; 1 leaf + 3 leaves (Box 88, Folder 17)
      London; Dear Mrs. Loewe, This is just a note of sympathy which please do not trouble to answer. [With second TLS dated Nov. 19, 1947 and an ALS from Julia Loewe to David Higham, as well as an ALS to Janice Biala to Julia Loewe, dated Nov. 10, 1947.] [Julian Loewe papers]
    - Pedrick, Gale TLS to Ford, Feb.27, 1906; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 18)
      London; Dear Sir, We beg to sincerely thank you for your favour of the 24th inst., [Lamb collection]
    - Peirce, Waldo ALS to Janice Biala, Dec.1, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 19)
      Pomona; Dear Biala- Have wanted to answer yr good letter long before this. Have been busy with two murals
    - Peirce, Waldo ALS to Ford & Janice Biala, May 25, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 20)
      Bangor; Dear Biala atque Fordus (All the latin I know) Thanks from both ambi muchas graciassisiuas [sic]
    - Pennell, Elizabeth R. ALS to Ford, Aug.26, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 21)
      New York; Dear Mr. Ford, I am in bed, with a Doctor and two nurses in attendance
    - Perkins, James A ALS to Arthur Mizener, [n.d.]; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 88, Folder 22)
      [New York] Arthur- Congratulations! The NY Times review was warm -- you should be pleased
    - Phillips, Cecil Ernest Lucas TLS to Violet Hunt, Mar.14, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 23)
      London; Dear Mrs. Hueffer, Thank you for your letter of March 12th. Lady Lucas was incorrect in supposing [Violet Hunt papers]
    - Phillips, Stephen ALS to Violet Hunt, Jul.9, 1890; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 88, Folder 24)
      London; Dear Miss Hunt/ Thank you very much for your letter. I told you I did not think I could come on Sunday,
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Janice Biala, Dec.1, 1937; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 25)
      [n.p.] Dear Mrs. Ford-- or as I say in my mind, Biala (forgiv me?) if this finds you at all,
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Janice Biala, [1938?]; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 26)
      [n.p.] Dear Janice-- Hurray for the book! I was not a little worried about the amount of lecturing they had Mr. Ford
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Janice Biala, [1938]; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 27)
      Janice darling -- your letter came today and though I will see you next week sometime I must tell you how very sorry
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Janice Biala, Jun.27, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 28)
      [n.p.] Dear Janice-- I thought your idea of coming to Olivet ahead of the Conference and settling down for a month
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Janice Biala, Sept.19, [1938]; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 29)
      [n.p.] Dearest Janice: I can't thank you enough for letting me know where you have gone
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Janice Biala, [1939]; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 30)
      [n.p.] Janice darling: You have been on my mind so constantly, have worried for fear Ford would get this terrible flu
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Ford, Aug.5, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 31)
      [n.p.] Dear Ford-- The copy of the letter from Houghton Mifflin that I am enclosing gave me a great deal of pleasure
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Ford, Oct.12, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 32)
      [n.p.] Dear Ford: I am mailing the manuscript of my book today and I am sorry that I couldn't send it
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Ford & Janice Biala, Mar.14, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 33)
      [n.p.] Dear Ford and Janice-- How good and how generous of your time and interest you always are --
    - Pickard, Wanda Tower TLS to Ford, May 22, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 88, Folder 34)
      [n.p.] Dear Ford: I was surprised to hear from Mr. Shively at Stokes today -- your kindness in my behalf
    - Pillement, Georges ALS to Ford, Mar.27, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 35)
      Paris; Mon cher ami, J'ai vu hier ma collaboratrice. La preface et les deux premiers chapitres sont deja traduits
    - Pillement, Georges TLS to Ford, Jun.1, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 36)
      Paris; Cher ami,Ci-joint la suite de la traduction jusqu's la fin du deuxieme chapitre
    - Pillement, Georges ALS to Ford, Jul.17, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 37)
      St. Ay; Cher ami, Je suis tres heureux que "Jaune et Rouge" vous plaise et je
    - Pillement, Georges TLS to Ford, Aug.11, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 38)
      Nice; Cher ami, Je suppose que vous etes toujours au Cap Brun. Sauf contre ordre de votre part
    - Pillement, Georges ALS to Ford & Janice Biala, Dec.26, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 39)
      Paris; Chers amis, Nous sommes tres touches de votre attention et du joli dessin si delicat
    - Pillement, Georges ALS to Ford, Jun.18, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 40)
      Paris; Cher ami, J'ai mene le manuscrit de ma traduction a Redier le lendemain meme du jour
    - Pillement, Georges ALS to Ford, Mar.5, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 41)
      Paris; Cher ami, Je suis tres touche de votre si gentille lettre et suis vraiment tres heureux que ma traduction
    - Pinker, James B. AD Ford Account Statement, Nov.30, 1904; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 42)
      London [Used name of Hueffer then] [Lamb collection]
    - James B. Pinker & Sons AD/TD Ford and Stella Bown Account Statements, 1926-1939; 40 leaves (Box 88, Folder 43)
      London; [39 statements of account between Pinker and Ford 1 between Pinker and Bowen]
    - James B. Pinker & Son TLS to J. M. Ashworth, Apr.24, 1924; 1 leaf (Box 88, Folder 44)
      London; Dear Madam, I have just received a remittance from America, and I am sending you [Signed Eric S. Pinker]